SHUBHAM BOMBARDE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Pune, India +91 8149136545 shubhambombarde4@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/shubhambombarde github.com/shubhambombarde

I am a seasoned Software Developer with nearly 5 years of expertise in crafting exceptional frontend features using React (Next JS), GraphQL, and TypeScript. My ability to excel in technical aspects and effectively execute tasks ensures product quality. I excel in collaborative environments, communicating complex concepts effectively. My passion for excellence makes me a valuable asset to any software development team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend - React, NextJS, TypeScript, React Query, Redux, Cypress, Storybook

Animation - Framer Motion, CSS

AWS - Cognito, Appsync, CaptchaPython - Django & flask, Machine Learning

PUBLICATION

 Published thesis in Springer titled "Livability- Analysis of People's Living Comfort in Different Cities of India Using GIS: A Prototype" (ref https://www.link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-030-46540-7_5)

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2022 - current

Software Engineer

Zuju Digital, Singapore

- Engineered high-performing, user-friendly front-end features for the user application and back-office systems, resulting in a 20% improvement in user satisfaction and a 15% increase in operational efficiency.
- Worked closely with UX/UI designers to translate design wireframes into responsive, and animations into interactive web applications.
- Orchestrated seamless integration and maintained platform consistency by collaborating with cross-functional teams, comprising backend developers and designers. Proactively identified communication misalignments, resulting in a remarkable 20% reduction in development time.
- Dedicated to continuous learning, I stayed abreast of the latest frontend trends and technologies, that included Next JS features and the seamless integration of GitHub Copilot into workflow processes. Proactively made recommendations for tech stack enhancements, such as advocating for the adoption of Static page generation to optimize load times (~30% faster) and overall system efficiency.

TOKIGAMES, Singapore

- Developed robust and efficient front-end code for the company's platform, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Implemented and optimized the user app, enhancing its performance and ensuring its alignment with business objectives (~50% faster).
- Proactively identified and resolved bottlenecks and bugs, employing strategic problem-solving techniques to minimize system downtime and enhance overall performance.
- Contributed to the creation and upkeep of documentation (70% coverage), assisting in onboarding new team members and serving as a knowledge base for ongoing development.

Software Engineer

July 2019 - February 2021

Searce, India

- Developed and maintained a robust platform for a movie production company, facilitating real-time tracking of progress, financials, and pre-production planning. This helped them move 60% of their unorganised data into our centralised platform.
- Demonstrated proficiency in both frontend and backend development, ensuring efficient, testable, and scalable code.
- Collaborated closely with an overseas client, providing them with vital development assistance, and ensuring their project met stipulated benchmarks and quality standards.
- Played a key role in the digital transformation of a traditional newspaper agency, spearheading their transition to a web-based platform. Over 55% of the user-base migrated and continued using the online platform.

EDUCATION

PGD in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence

2020 - 2021

IIIT, Bangalore, India

Bachelor in Computer Engineering

2015 - 2019

MIT Academy of Engineering, Pune, India

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Problem Solving Critical Thinking Decision Making Attention to Detail